<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible ICD Conversion With ATHENA and R</title>
      <link>/2020/09/25/reproducible-icd-conversion-with-athena-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/25/reproducible-icd-conversion-with-athena-and-r/</guid>
      <description>Why Bother?If you work with diagnosis data, you’re likely to encounter ICD codes. ICD (Internal Classification of Diseases) is a globally used set codes that hierarchically classifies diagnoses, symptoms, and other clinical observations. Since the adoption of the Electronic Health Records (EHR), the primary revision of ICD in use ICD-9. At least, that was so until October 1st, 2015, when the United States made a nationwide switch to ICD-10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics of the Health Information Exchange in the Era of Data Science</title>
      <link>/2020/09/22/ethics-of-the-health-information-exchange-in-the-era-of-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/22/ethics-of-the-health-information-exchange-in-the-era-of-data-science/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionHealth Information Exchanges (HIEs) allow for the transfer and storage of EHR data across institutions, with the primary use of improving patient care (Health IT 2020). The combination of multiple EHRs creates a wealth of data that can also be attractive for secondary uses such as research. Recent advances in machine learning and data science have enabled the analysis of HIE data in unanticipated ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Create a Practice OMOP Dataset in R</title>
      <link>/2020/09/22/how-to-create-a-practice-omop-dataset-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/22/how-to-create-a-practice-omop-dataset-in-r/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe use of electronic health record (EHR) data is common and often necessary in clinical research. These data can be cumbersome and complicated, yet inaccessible due to privacy laws. My goal in this post is to set the reader up with a “fake” clinical dataset so that they can learn the ins and out of EHR data and feel more prepared when they encounter the real thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Post</title>
      <link>/2020/09/21/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/21/test-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a testYep. This is what it looks like– This line here is to test continuous integration.
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>